AI coding tools can produce an impressive first answer in seconds.
But impressive is not the same as engineered.
That first response may hide missed requirements, fragile error handling, weak accessibility, or code
that becomes difficult to maintain.
DevLoop AI changes the stopping point. It treats generation as the beginning of a
visible engineering process.
For every requirement, DevLoop plans the approach, generates a solution, reviews it, scores it,
and improves it when needed.
The application owns this loop. It stops when quality reaches eighty-five, or after a
hard maximum of three reviewed iterations.
Here is the deployed product running with OpenAI live.
I am asking for a minimal Python project with packaging, source code, tests, Git
ignore rules, and setup instructions.
The interface exposes each stage as it happens: planning, generating, reviewing, and, when required,
improving the result.
The backend makes separate structured calls, validates every response, and streams progress to the
Angular interface with server-sent events.
This live result received an overall quality score of ninety-four on its first reviewed
version.
Because it already cleared the threshold, DevLoop stopped after iteration one.
Stopping early here is expected behavior, not a missing loop.
The result is scored across correctness, maintainability, security, accessibility, performance, and requirement coverage.
Judges can inspect the plan, review findings, applied changes, generated output, and the exact
stop condition instead of seeing only a final answer.
The preview is correctly labelled Python, rather than displaying a fixed filename from another
framework.
For project-scaffolding prompts, DevLoop also returns a structured file manifest.
This run produced six complete project files.
The package can be downloaded as a ZIP for local inspection, while nested paths
and unsafe filenames are validated before archive creation.
The architecture stays intentionally focused: Angular for the experience, Express and TypeScript for orchestration,
and OpenAI Structured Outputs for model responses.
API keys remain on the server. Zod validates the model data, and the application—not
the model—controls the iteration limit.
Quality scores are structured model evaluations. DevLoop does not execute, compile, or security-audit generated
code.
That honest boundary keeps the project practical while making AI improvement transparent, measurable, and
easy to demonstrate.
DevLoop AI. Better first drafts come from visible engineering, because the first answer is
just the beginning.